JESSICA YAU

ABOUT ME

An enthusiastic and self-motivated Software Engineer based in Boston, MA. Experienced in designing and building user-friendly full-stack web applications from the ground up. Passionate about innovating and creating interactive digital experiences, and capable of finding creative solutions to problems.



(857) 928-4826



jess.yau051@gmail.com iessicayau.net



linkedin.com/in/jessyau

github.com/jessicayau

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts in Biology

Boston University, Boston, MA May 2009

CERTIFICATIONS

Google Data Analytics

May 2021

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages

JavaScript (ES6+), Python 3, SQL, HTML. CSS/Sass

Libraries/Frameworks

Django, Django REST Framework, Flask, React, Redux, Gatsby, Styled Components, Bootstrap

Tools

Firebase, NPM, Git, Netlify, Heroku

PROJECTS

Envisioned, Color palette visualizer and generator

https://envisioned.netlify.app I https://github.com/jessicayau/envisioned

- Built with JavaScript, React, Redux, Firebase, and Styled Components
- Designed and developed a color palette inspiration web application for users to visualize curated, as well as custom-created, color palettes applied to demo templates to get an idea of how the colors could be used together for light or dark modes, gradients, or text and background color combinations

Potted, E-commerce plant shop

https://potted.netlify.app I https://github.com/jessicayau/potted

- Built with JavaScript, React, Redux/Redux-Saga, Firebase, and Styled Components
- Designed and created a fully-responsive e-commerce website with an array of products, each with its own details page, an editable shopping cart and checkout page, a favorites page, payment processing handled by Stripe, and Google/email account creation and login

Blog, Personal Blog

https://jess-blog.herokuapp.com | https://github.com/jessicayau/jess-blog

- Built with Python, Django, PostgreSQL, Bootstrap, CKEditor, and AWS S3
- Designed and developed a fully-functional blog with Django that features user authentication, an admin dashboard, user commenting, and a WYSIWYG rich text editor for text and images, and supports CRUD operations (create, read, update, delete blog posts)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

MANA Products, Long Island City, NY

Chemist II, Research and Development, October 2018 – August 2020 Chemist I, Research and Development, October 2014 – October 2018 Junior Chemist, Research and Development, March 2013 – October 2014

- Specialized in the research, development, and testing of powder cosmetics
- Responsible for working on product development requests, shade matching, formulating, sample preparation, stability tests, and reworking/adjusting production batches with to match approved standards
- Collaborated with contracting clients, product developers, and account managers to achieve cost-effective and innovative products with the desired formulation, application, shade, and claims
- Partnered with cross-functional teams to develop and modernize methods for commercialization of new development projects
- Communicated with vendors regarding raw materials specifications, discrepancies, samples, and new products and ideas